did you guys know that blender 4.0 had a
你们知道吗 搅拌机4.0有一个
change that makes it more realistic by
通过以下方式使其更具现实性的变化
default or that there's a new technology
违约或者有一种新技术
that is going to expand the uses for 3D
这将扩大3D的用途
exponentially well you would if you were
如果你是的话 你会以指数级的方式
on my free newsletter called this week
在我的免费通讯《本周》上
in 3D it's an email from me once a week
在3D模式下 我每周发一封电子邮件
with three to five things that I found
带着我发现的三五件东西
interesting that week from the world of
有趣的一周 来自世界各地的
3D so sometimes I share a new tool that
3D所以有时我会分享一个新工具
I found a remarkable tutorial a new
我发现了一个很棒的教程 一个新的
blender feature a new news story that
搅拌机以一则新的新闻故事为特色
affects the industry so click the link
影响行业 因此请单击该链接
in the description enter your email
在描述中输入您的电子邮件
address and then you will stay up to
地址 然后你会一直呆到
date on the world of 3D it's always free
3D世界中的约会永远是免费的
and it's always written by me now on to
它总是由我写到现在
the tutorial welcome back to the donut
本教程欢迎回到甜甜圈
show where we make sad little Donuts
展示我们在哪里做悲伤的小甜甜圈
that we cannot eat this is where we
我们不能吃这就是我们
finished up at the end of part one we've
在第一部分的末尾我们已经完成了
got our nice looking dut and now we're
得到了我们漂亮的灰尘 现在我们
going to make that icing which looks
去做看起来像是糖衣的糖衣
complex but is actually fairly simple
很复杂 但实际上相当简单
now as I mentioned before if you want to
就像我之前提到的 如果你想
add an object you go shift a right and
添加一个对象 然后右移
then you start with something that
然后你从一些东西开始
resembles what you're trying to create
与您正在尝试创建的内容类似
but we already have something that
但我们已经有了一些东西
resembles the exact shape we want to
与我们想要的形状一模一样
create it's the donut because we want
创造它是甜甜圈因为我们想要
the icing around the donut so let's just
甜甜圈周围的糖霜所以我们就
reuse this information so we can do that
重复使用这些信息 这样我们就可以这样做了
by duplicating the object um and if you
通过复制对象um 如果您
don't know the hotkey for it you could
不知道它的热键你可以
just go object and then you'd find it uh
只要去反对 然后你就会发现 嗯
here where it says shift d so shift d
这里写着Shift d所以Shift d
now when you hit that you are in a
现在 当你击球时 你是在一个
placement State essentially like it's
放置状态基本上就像它
duplicated and it's now saying whereit
复制了一份 现在说它在哪里
you want to place it now in our case and
你现在想把它放在我们的案子里
actually often you don't actually want
其实很多时候你其实并不想
to change its placement you want to
要更改其位置 请执行以下操作
duplicate it exactly where it was so you
把它复制到原来的位置 这样你就
can cancel the movement by hitting
可以通过点击取消移动
Escape or right clicking now when you do
执行操作时立即退出或单击鼠标右键
that it looks like it's canceled the
它看起来像是取消了
duplication but you can see in your
复制 但您可以在您的
outliner it has duplicated it you've got
大纲 它已经复制了你已经得到的
two objects but um it's just in the
两个物体 但呃 它就在
exact same place which is what we want
完全一样的地方 这就是我们想要的
so first things first um we need to name
所以首先 嗯 我们需要命名
them or else we could get very confused
否则我们会很困惑的
very easily so you can name an object by
非常容易 因此您可以通过以下方式命名对象
just double clicking it in the outliner
只需在大纲视图中双击它
and then just typing in the object the
然后只需在对象中键入
other way you can name something I'll
否则你可以说出我的名字
just show you the second way if you
只要告诉你第二条路 如果你
select the
选择
taurus1 that's your icing object if
这是你的结冰对象 如果
you're in the 3D view where your cursor
您在3D视图中 您的光标位于
sorry is over the 3D view Port if you
抱歉 如果您在3D视图端口上
hit F2 that's another very quick way
按F2键 这是另一种非常快速的方法
that you can uh name something without
你可以 呃 在没有名字的情况下
having to go out up to the outliner to
不得不走到大纲图上去
find your object so with our icing
用我们的糖衣找到你的物品
object selected let's go into edit mode
对象已选定 让我们进入编辑模式
by hitting tab so we want the icing on
通过按Tab键 所以我们想要锦上添花
the top which means this bottom half of
上半部分 也就是下半部分
our mesh here is redundant don't need it
我们这里的网络是多余的 不需要它
so we want to delete it so if we just
所以我们想删除它 所以如果我们只是
dragged over the bottom here you can see
拖到底部 你可以看到
it looks like we've selected the bottom
看起来我们已经选择了底部
half of our donut but if you were to
我们一半的甜甜圈 但如果你
move around you would see oh we haven't
四处走动 你会看到 哦 我们还没有
actually it's only selected annoyingly
实际上 它只是被恼人地选中了
uh what is facing the camera where
呃 面对着摄像机的是什么
there's a mesh it's not gone through the
有一个网状物 它没有穿过
mesh a lot of users find this uh
网罗很多用户都觉得这个呢
annoying I agree sometimes it's seems
很烦人 我同意有时这看起来
like that would be the more default one
就像那会是更默认的那样
that would make more sense but anyway
这会更有意义 但不管怎样
don't want to argue
我不想争辩
um so if you want to select through a
嗯 所以如果您想通过
mesh you can go up to here in your your
您可以在您的Mesh上找到此处
top navigation toggle x-ray if you turn
顶部导航切换x射线 如果您将
that on it's going to enable you to see
它会让你看到
through the mesh and now when I drag
穿过网格 现在当我拖动时
over it you can see that I have uh
在它上面你可以看到我有呃
selected all through the mesh as I move
在我移动时在整个网格中选择
around it by the way you might find it
顺便说一句 你可能会找到它
like when you're in this state it's kind
就像当你处于这种状态时 感觉很好
of hard to select like it's easy to kind
很难选择 就像很容易分类一样
of accidentally select what is above it
意外地选择了它上面的内容
and depending on what you've got at your
这取决于你在你的
end that might have happened um already
结束可能已经发生的事情 嗯
so another way to easily just look
所以另一种简单的方式就是
directly on the side on of your uh donut
就在你的呃甜甜圈的边上
is to just click one of these um like in
只需点击其中一个 就像在
your Gizmo here instead of just dragging
你的Gizmo在这里 而不是只是拖拽
around just do a single click on either
只需在任何一个上点击一下
the green one or the red one the x or
绿色的或红色的x或
the Y and now we're in that state you
Y 现在我们处于这样的状态 你
can see it's it's flattened it so it's
可以看到它是它被压平了所以它
put you in orthographic mode which
让你进入正射模式
actually you can toggle to at any time
实际上 您可以随时切换到
just over there which just makes it
就在那里 这正好让它
easier to just do a single all the way
全程只做一次单曲更容易
through the mesh um select all right
通过网格 嗯 选择好的
okay all right so we want to delete that
好的 好的 我们想把它删除
so just hit the delete key you get an
所以只需按Delete键 您就会得到一个
extra option here of what do you want to
这里有额外的选项 您想要什么
delete edges faces you want the vertices
删除想要的折点的边面
that's everything and now we have if we
这就是一切 现在我们有了 如果我们
go back to uh object mode and then let's
返回到对象模式 然后让我们
turn off toggle x-ray as well and you
关闭切换x光也会让你
can see it's uh it's working we got half
可以看到它 呃 它起作用了 我们得到了一半
the the doughnut on top of itself but as
甜甜圈在它自己的上面 但作为
you move around you can see you got some
你四处走动 你会看到你得到了一些
flickering now this flickering happens
闪烁现在这个闪烁发生了
and it's actually a very common it's
事实上 这是一种非常常见的
actually a good warning sign to you as
实际上对你来说是一个很好的警告信号
an artist cuz it means you've got uh
艺术家 因为这意味着你有呃
faces on top of faces and the 3D
面上的面和3D
software doesn't know which face it
软件不知道它面对的是谁
wants to render right so it's like
想要正确地渲染 所以就像
sometimes saying it's the the front face
有时会说这是一张脸
no the back face the front face and
不 背面 正面 还有
there's no understanding sometimes you
有时候你不会理解
can actually spot it in TV shows and
我可以在电视节目中发现它
like VFX or like lowbudget stuff you can
比如VFX或低预算的东西
see something flickering in the
看到有什么东西在闪烁
background and I'm like ooh there it is
背景 我就像 哦 就是这样
Z fighting um that's what it's called Z
战斗 嗯 这就是它所说的
Z fighting or Zed fighting if you're not
Z战斗或Zed战斗 如果你不是
American so what we want to do is we
美国人所以我们想要做的是我们
want to give uh thickness to our icing
想要给我们的糖衣增加厚度吗？
so we can do that with a solidifier
所以我们可以用固化剂做到这一点
modifier so adding another modifier make
修改器 因此添加另一个修改器使
sure you've got your icing selected not
当然 你的糖衣已经选好了
your donut and then here where you've
你的甜甜圈 然后在这里你已经
got add modifier we're going to go
添加修饰语 我们要开始了
generate solidify okay now it's made it
生成固化好的 现在它成功了
worse it's uh it's actually added a
更糟糕的是 呃 它实际上增加了一个
thickness to our uh mesh there but it's
厚度到我们的呃网眼 但它是
actually done it the wrong way so it's
实际上是以错误的方式做的 所以
with the normals yeah what is it it's
在正常的情况下是的这是什么
trying to put the uh the extra bit
试着把这个额外的部分
inside the dut so we can change that by
所以我们可以改变这一点
just changing the offset here in the
只需在此处更改
solidifier settings just drag that all
凝固器设置只需拖动所有
the way to one some of you might have
你们中的一些人可能拥有的方法
actually found that it was correct
实际上发现它是正确的
before just depending on which way your
在此之前 只是取决于你的方式
normals were if that's the case keep it
正常的是 如果是这样的话 留着它
at minus one but everyone else keep it
在负一 但其他人保持它
at one we just want to make sure it's
有一次 我们只想确保
actually outside okay um I also let's
其实在外面 好的 嗯 我也让我们
just increase the thickness a little bit
只需增加一点厚度即可
too let's go here
我也是 我们去这里吧
0.25 that looks pretty good and uh great
0.25美元 看起来很不错 呃 很棒
we've got got what looks like a yarma on
我们穿上了看起来像是Yarma的衣服
our donut a perfectly
我们的甜甜圈是完美的
straightedge little hat for our donut so
为我们的甜甜圈拉直小帽子
let's make this look more like icing so
让我们让这看起来更像糖霜
the edge is wavy all the way around so
边缘一直是波浪形的 所以
to do this this is where we get into the
要做到这一点 这就是我们进入
fancy ooh finger magic um cuz you're
神奇的手指 嗯 因为你是
typing lots of keys anyway um go into
不管怎样都要打很多键 嗯 进入
edit mode and we can see straight away
编辑模式 我们可以直接看到
that we can't see uh the man and that's
我们看不到 呃 那个人 那是
because the solidify modify is
因为固化修饰剂是
obstructing our view so these little
挡住了我们的视线 所以这些
boxes here as I mentioned before like
就像我之前提到的 这里的箱子
this is to hide it from viewport um but
这是为了从视区中隐藏它 但是
if you want to just hide it from your
如果你想把它藏起来不让你的
edit mode which is the state that we are
编辑模式 这是我们所处的状态
in right now the box next to it is the
现在 它旁边的框是
one that you uh uncheck which means in
一个你 呃 取消勾选 这意味着
object mode when you're tabbed in object
当您在对象中设置为选项卡时的对象模式
mode you can still see it but edit mode
模式您仍然可以看到它 但编辑模式
it's uh whoops it's temporarily hidden
它呃 哎呀 它暂时被藏起来了
for you so if I was to select one of
对你来说 所以如果我选择一个
these points here and move it down you
这些点在这里 然后把它移到你的下面
can see that uh it's it's working but
可以看到 呃 它在工作 但是
but it would be again a lot of effort to
但这将再次付出巨大的努力来
go round and round and do these one by
转来转去 一个接一个地做这些
one so we want to use that uh old
一个 所以我们想用那个呃旧的
familiar proportional fall-off tool
常见的比例落下工具
again so proportional editing on and now
再次开启比例编辑 现在
as I move it down let's just uh let's
当我把它移下来的时候 让我们 呃 让我们
just lower the slide way down here and
把滑道放下来 然后
then let's pull this down okay now we'll
那么让我们把这个拉下来 好的 现在我们
find issues if we move to the side here
如果我们移到一边 找出问题
we can see the first issue we've
我们可以看到我们的第一期
discovered is that this is separating
发现的是 这是分离的
from our mesh here and that's not what
从我们这里的网状结构来看 这不是
icing does when it dribbles down it
当糖霜顺着它流下来的时候 它就会
follows the shape of the D all the way
一直沿用D的形状
down so what we want to do is snap oops
向下 所以我们要做的是抓紧时间
undo it a number of times snap the uh
将其撤消多次 然后将其扣住
snap the vertices to our dut underneath
将顶点捕捉到我们下面的DUT
it right so for that we need to turn on
是的 所以我们需要打开
snapping up here okay now there are a
在这里抢购好的 现在有一个
number of ways to snap in blender the
将搅拌机卡入搅拌机的几种方法
default way is increment which just
默认方式是递增 只是
means the uh like the grid floor there
意思是 呃 就像那边的格子地板
like if you were to just like move it
就像你把它搬开一样
around you can see it's just snapping to
在你的周围 你可以看到它正在猛烈地跳动
the grid floor not helpful but we want
网格地板没有帮助 但我们希望
to snap it to the face and now with face
捕捉到它的脸 现在用脸
snapping enabled if we move this down we
启用捕捉如果我们将此位置向下移动
can see let's just look here that the
可以看到 让我们看看这里
bottom bit is snapping to the face but
底部的钻头咬到了脸 但
as you might have seen the top bits the
正如您可能已经看到的最上面的部分
rest of uh essentially what is inside of
其余的 呃 基本上是里面的东西
our circle of influence with this
我们在这方面的影响力
proportional editing that's not being a
比例编辑 这不是一个
affected only the little point that we
只影响了一个小问题 我们
had selected was affected so that's not
已选择的内容受影响 因此不会
what we want either normally that would
我们通常想要的也不是
be enough but in this particular case we
足够了 但在这种特殊情况下 我们
want to also snap individual elements to
我还想将单个元素捕捉到
and let's go face project now when we
现在让我们面对项目 当我们
pull this down you should see that these
把这个往下拉 你应该看到这些
are also no longer clipping through the
也不再通过剪裁
dut but still we have issues why is that
但是我们仍然有问题 为什么呢？
well it is actually working correctly we
嗯 它实际上工作正常 我们
can see these are not going through the
可以看到这些都没有经过
mesh so why does it look like it is the
那么为什么它看起来像是
reason for that is that there's actually
其原因是 实际上
just not enough information here so if
只是这里没有足够的信息 所以如果
we go side on you can see right like
我们站在一边 你可以看到就像
we've got this Point uh here and then
我们有这一点 呃 这里 然后
we've got another Point down here and
我们在这下面还有一个点
then we've got this long stretch uh in
然后我们有很长的一段时间 呃
between right so that means that this
在右边 所以这意味着这个
part of the Donut oh gosh that goes that
甜甜圈的一部分哦 天哪 是这样的
goes around like that is just not
像这样到处走来走去不是
there's nothing to snap it to
没有什么可以抓住它的
essentially so what we need to do to fix
从本质上说 我们需要做的是修复
this is just add more geometry so these
这只是添加更多的几何图形 所以这些
little vertices here we need more of
这里的小顶点 我们需要更多
those vertices so we can do that by
这些顶点 所以我们可以通过
actually using the subdivision
实际上使用的是细分
surface modifier cuzz although it is a
曲面修改器cuzz 尽管它是
modifier you can apply the modifier and
修改器您可以应用修改器和
the modifier currently is adding
修改器当前正在添加
geometry so let's just apply it so to
几何学 让我们把它应用到
apply it we just click this little drop
应用它 我们只需点击这一小滴
down here next to the modifier and then
在修饰符旁边 然后
go apply now if we I mean nothing should
现在去申请吧 如果我们我的意思是什么都不应该
have changed from this view because the
已与此视图不同 因为
same information is being displayed but
正在显示相同的信息 但
in edit mode you should now see
在编辑模式下 您现在应该会看到
exponentially more faces cuz here where
更多的面孔 因为在这里
there was uh you know one face before
呃 你知道以前有一张脸
you can see there's now a lot more right
你可以看到现在有更多的权利
d uh four 4X okay 4X um okay so now if
D 四个4X好的 4X好的 那么现在如果
we pull down we should see it is
我们拉下来 我们应该看到它是
snapping and if we go into this mode you
抓拍 如果我们进入此模式 您
can see that it's now conforming to the
可以看到 它现在符合
mesh in a much more uh snug way cuz
以一种更舒适的方式网罗 因为
there's information there for it to use
那里有它可以使用的信息
now this shading artifact here that we
现在这件阴影艺术品 我们
can see this this don't worry about that
我能看到这个这个不用担心那个
we'll fix that in just a moment but uh I
我们很快就会解决这个问题 但是呃我
need to show cuz I've shown you like
我需要展示给你 因为我已经展示给你喜欢
four things that we need to enable for
我们需要启用以下四项功能
this work I got to show you one more uh
这件作品我要再给你看一件
because if I pull down and if I scroll
因为如果我向下拉 如果我滚动
up you'll see something okay if I was to
在上面你会看到一些东西 如果我去
click we get this horrible uh problem
点击我们得到了这个可怕的呃问题
here and I've done this tutorial and
下面是我做过的这个教程和
enough and enough people have hit this
已经有足够多的人袭击了这里
issue that I need to call it out
我需要把它叫出来
specifically because it seems to be a
特别是因为它似乎是一种
big point that a lot of people just
重要的一点是 很多人只是
don't know where to go from um what's
不知道从哪里去 嗯 什么
happened is if we use a uh this uh
发生的情况是如果我们用这个这个
what's it called the the the the circle
这个圆叫什么来着？
of influence for our proportional
对我们比例的影响
editing if that is so high it's actually
编辑如果真的这么高 那实际上
high enough to reach the mesh on the
高度足够高 可以到达
other side of the donut and then because
甜甜圈的另一面 然后因为
we've got snapping it's now projecting
我们已经抓拍了 现在它正在投射
that snapping it to the front which is
把它扣到前面 这就是
creating this like something that's a
创造这个 就像是一种
nightmare to fix I me in fact it's
噩梦把我治好其实这是
easier just to start from scratch than
白手起家比白手起家容易
to try to fix that so if we want sorry
试着修复它 所以如果我们想要道歉
there's a lot of noise uh to fix this we
有很多噪音 呃 来解决这个问题
need to hide the part of the mesh that
需要隐藏网格的一部分
we don't want to be uh influenced by our
我们不想呃受我们的
uh proportional tool right so to do that
呃 比例工具对了 这样做是正确的
there is an easy way to do it uh we can
有一个简单的方法来做 呃 我们可以的
actually do it very precisely so if with
实际上做得非常准确 所以如果用
this middle bit of our donut here if I
我们甜甜圈的中间这一块如果我
just hold down alt and then do a left
只要按住Alt 然后向左转
click as I mentioned before that selects
如我之前提到的 点击选择
the ring okay and we could you know we
戒指没问题 我们能不能你知道我们
could do that all the way up but
可以一直做下去 但是
actually there's a little uh I don't
实际上 有一点 呃 我没有
know if it's an Easter egg it's kind of
如果它是一个复活节彩蛋 它就是一种
a cool tool that not people know not
一个不为人所知的酷工具
many people know about Control Plus H
很多人都知道Control Plus H
that will enable these select more tool
这将启用这些选择更多工具
and if you use control+ contrl minus
如果你使用Ctrl+Ctrl减号
goes the other way you can see that it's
往另一边走 你可以看到它是
expanding out so Control Plus will just
向外扩展 以便Control Plus
like select the next verticy along a
就像选择沿
chain roughly speaking um and you can
粗略地说 链条 嗯 你可以
see we can very quickly select all the
看 我们可以非常快速地选择所有
parts of the mesh that we don't need
我们不需要的部分网格
right very cool by the way if Control
对 顺便说一句 非常酷 如果控制
Plus doesn't work for you cuz you're on
加号对你不起作用 因为你在
a laptop or something else select more
笔记本电脑或其他设备 选择更多
less you can also do it here anyways to
更少的你也可以在这里做 无论如何
hide this part of the mesh it's h h for
隐藏网格的这一部分 它是h h h
hide so when you're in this state it
隐藏起来 这样当你处于这种状态时
looks as though it's been deleted it's
看起来好像已经被删除了
very sometimes you don't know where part
很多时候 你不知道在哪里
of your mesh and then you forgot that
然后你就忘了这一点
you've got hide turned on um if parts of
你已经打开了隐藏 嗯 如果有部分
your mesh are hidden and you want to
您的网格处于隐藏状态 并且您希望
bring it back it's alt H so H to hide
把它带回来它是Alt H所以H要藏起来
and then alt H to bring it back or if
然后按Alt H将其带回来 或者如果
you can't remember it for whatever
你无论如何都不能记住它
reason you can also find it okay it's
因为你也能找到它 好的
underneath mesh there we go mesh uh
在网眼下面 我们开始网眼 嗯
reveal hidden or hide selected okay so
显示隐藏或隐藏所选内容确定 这样做
that's the other way but you can get my
这是另一种方式 但你可以拿到我的
keyboard shortcut that it's in the link
它在链接中的键盘快捷键
it's free just use that and then you
它是免费的 只需使用它 然后你就可以
won't forget a lot of these handy
不会忘记很多这样方便的东西
shortcuts all right so now finally after
所有的捷径 所以现在终于过了
all that after four different ways of
在经历了四种不同的方式之后
and problems to explain we can now take
和要解释的问题 我们现在可以
part of this mesh and drag it down and
此网格的一部分 并将其向下拖动
it will work correctly haha so now we
它会正常工作的 哈哈 所以现在我们
just make we get to now finally be an
只是让我们现在终于成为一名
artist and go like what sort of uh you
艺术家 走什么样的人 嗯 你
know Edge or you know what sort of icing
了解Edge或者你知道哪种糖霜
do I want to make this look like so what
我想让它看起来像这样吗？那又怎么样
I'm doing here by the way is I'm I'm h G
顺便说一句 我在这里做的是我是我是HG
to pull it down and then I'm just middle
把它拉下来 然后我就在中间
click single middle click and then
单击鼠标中键并单击 然后
because my cursor is closest to the Zed
因为我的光标离ZED最近
axis it's now snapping it to the Zed
轴 它现在正在将它捕捉到ZED上
axis so that's why I mentioned before
轴心 这就是我之前提到的原因
that it's uh it's really handy you don't
它 呃 它真的很方便 你不需要
have to think of the letter and type it
我得想一想这封信 然后把它打出来
in you just go in the general direction
你只要往大方向走就行了
you want to go and then just tap the
你想走了 然后点击
middle click of the uh which is your
点击鼠标中键 呃 这是你的
your scroll wheel right middle middle
你的滚轮右边中间中间
click it's such a weird uh button that
点击它是如此奇怪的一个按钮
you have to call it out it's the scroll
你得把它叫出来 这是卷轴
wheel button cuz like no other
车轮按钮 因为它独一无二
application seems to use it besides
应用程序似乎还在使用它
scrolling but blender is like no we're
滚动但搅拌机就像不我们是
going to use it for like 90% of the
大约90%的人都会用到它
operations is going to be middle click
操作将按鼠标中键
um but anyways I as you can see I'm not
嗯 但不管怎样 我 如你所见 我不是
paying particularly too much attention
特别是太过关注
to it but I'm just making a wavy looking
但我只是做了个波浪式的看
shape around it um you might also want
围绕它的形状 嗯 你可能还想要
to make some bits that go the opposite
做一些与之相反的东西
direction right and then maybe pull so
正确的方向 然后可能拉这样
you've got like big shapes as well as
你有很大的体型 还有
medium shapes and some small shapes big
中等形状和一些小形状大的
medium small it's the uh it's the recipe
中号的 呃 这是食谱
for appealing design big medium and
为吸引人的设计大媒体和
small details but uh I digress by the
小细节 但是 呃 我离题了
way I should mention if you're stuck
我应该提醒你 如果你被困在
don't feel bad cuz there was certainly a
别难过 因为肯定有一场
lot of uh a lot of finickiness going on
很多 呃 很多财务问题正在发生
with this donut here and uh it's yeah
带着这个甜甜圈 呃 是的
it's a we're definitely in the Steep
这是一个我们肯定在陡峭的地方
part of that curve at the moment uh do
目前这条曲线的一部分 呃
make use of my Discord if you are stuck
如果你被卡住了 就利用我的不和吧
I created it literally so that people
我创造它的字面意思是为了让人们
could get instantaneous help I don't
可以得到即时的帮助 我不能
have any other benefit for it so it's
有任何其他的好处 所以它是
there so that you can can find help link
在那里 您可以找到帮助链接
is in the description and there's a
在描述中 有一个
donut help chat room where you can post
甜甜圈帮助聊天室 你可以在那里发帖
screenshots of your problem and then
您的问题屏幕截图 然后
people can help each other out so do
人们可以互相帮助 也可以这样做
make use of that now our shading issue
利用这一点 现在我们的阴影问题
here this darkened Edge is actually
这张变暗的边缘实际上是
going to fix itself by fixing another
通过修复另一个来修复自己
issue so it's a two birds one solution
所以这是一个两只鸟一个的解决方案
kind of problem uh this 90° edge here
有点问题 呃 这条90度的边
for this icing not ideal uh everybody
对于这种结冰并不理想 呃 每个人
knows that a real icing would create
知道真正的糖霜会创造出
like a rounded Edge there right so we
就像那里的圆边一样 所以我们
can fix that just by adding another
只需添加另一个即可修复
subsurf modifier cuz you might remember
Subsurf修改器 因为您可能记得
I mentioned like yes if you've got three
我说过 如果你有三个人的话
vertices it'll create like another
它将像另一个顶点一样创建顶点
verticy here and another verticy here
这里是垂直的 这里是另一个垂直的
but it'll also like round it out it'll
但它也会让它变得圆润起来
pull this one back so you end up with a
把这个拉回来 这样你就会得到一个
rounded corner so right here in your
圆角 就在你的这里
modifier stack we're going to go add
我们要添加的修改器堆栈
modify generate subdivision surface now
立即修改生成细分曲面
the order of these does matter okay you
这些东西的顺序很重要 好吧
want your your solidifier at the top and
我想让你的固化剂在上面
the subdivision after it so blender
在它之后的细分如此搅拌机
Works top to bottom and it's important
从上到下工作 这很重要
it's in this way because you want the
这样做是因为你想要
Extrusion to happen first and then in
先进行拉伸 然后再进行拉伸
order to round that edge it happens has
为了绕过它所发生的边缘
to happen as a secondary step so
作为次要步骤发生 所以
solidify on top subdivision underneath
固化在上面下面的细分上
now whilst we're here and we're looking
现在 当我们在这里 我们正在寻找
at the uh the closeup nice little
在 呃 特写镜头里 漂亮的小
profile of this edge of this icing
这块结冰边缘的轮廓
another issue to call it you can see
你可以看到另一个叫它的问题
it's got this uh this shape that goes
它有这个呃这个形状
around yes so far so good but then it
大约是的 到目前为止一切都很好 但后来
goes up and it's like m it would be
升起来 就像它会是
better if it went around and then tucked
如果它绕着它 然后塞起来会更好
in and touched the edge of it cuz that
并触摸到它的边缘 因为
would look more like real liquid wood so
看起来更像是真正的液态木材
we can solve that by just changing one
我们只要换一个就能解决这个问题
of the settings in the solidify modify
实体化修改中的设置的
it's not one of those things that you
这不是你想要的那种事情
would figure out or know where it is
会找出或知道它在哪里
it's just over time you learn where some
只是随着时间的推移 你会了解到
of these settings are but essentially
在这些设置中 主要是
here the edge data so we want to change
这里是边缘数据 所以我们想要更改
the edge data to say that uh before you
在你面前的边缘数据可以说
do the solidify step add a crease on the
固化步骤是否在上边添加折痕
inner part right here if we increase
就在这里 如果我们增加
this all the way way to one it now
一直到现在都是这样
creates a sharpened Edge just on that
在此基础上创建锐化边缘
inner part there so the rest of it is a
所以它的其余部分是一个
smoothed Edge but the middle one there's
平滑的边缘 但中间的那个
a crease so it's making a sharp edge
一道折痕 所以它的边缘很锋利
there and it just gives it just a little
在那里 它只是给了它一点
bit more realism just looks a little bit
更多的现实主义只是看起来有点
closer to what you would imagine real
更接近你想象的真实
icing would do okay now for the cool bit
冰激凌现在就可以做得很好了
all right so if you look at reference of
好的 如果你看一下参考文献
donuts right yes you've got these little
好的 是的 你有这些小甜甜圈
wavy bits but where the the icing is
波浪形的部分 但糖霜在哪里
really liquidy it'll often break off
真的很液态 它经常会断掉
from this wave here and it'll create a
从这里的这一波 它将创建一个
trail that goes down uh underneath the
那条小路 呃 一直延伸到
donut right it just sort of drips all
甜甜圈是这样的 只是有点滴水
the way down whoops bump the microphone
向下的路 哇 撞上了麦克风
so we can do that um but not what we the
所以我们可以这样做 嗯 但不是我们
way we were doing it before if we just
我们以前做的方式 如果我们只是
took one of these points and then like
拿到其中的一个点 然后就像
dragged it all the way down like that
就像那样一路拖下去
there wouldn't be enough information
不会有足够的信息
there right you can see you just get
就在那里 你可以看到你只是
this like stretched look and it doesn't
这看起来像是拉长的样子 但它不是
look great okay so essentially we need
看起来很棒 好的 所以基本上我们需要
to give it more information and we
为它提供更多信息 我们
couldn't just do it by like adding more
不能仅仅通过添加更多
and more subdivision servic we we need
我们需要更多细分服务
to actually like break this shape here
实际上就像打破这个形状
and create a new shape that goes down so
并创造一个新的形状 这样就可以
we need to extrude so if I select this
我们需要挤出 所以如果我选择此选项
verticy and then the one next to it by
垂直的 然后是它旁边的
holding down shift I don't think I
按住Shift我不认为我
mentioned it but yeah if you want to
我提过了 但如果你想的话
select two things at once it's shift
一次选择两件事它是Shift
select um anyways so if we select two
选择UM无论如何 所以如果我们选择两个
vertices like that we want to extrude it
像这样的顶点 我们想要挤出它
downward by hitting e so when you tap e
向下按e 这样当你点击e时
it's similar to G and that you're in a
它类似于G 你在一个
placement State now saying where do you
安置状态现在说你在哪里
want to place this so I'm going to move
我想把这个放好 所以我要搬家了
it down to yeah like about there where I
归根结底是这样 就像我在那里
want the trail to stop and I'm just
我想让这条路停下来 我只是
going to do click left click and it's
要做的是点击左键点击 它就是
now placed it there now if I it's hard
现在把它放在那里 如果我很难的话
to see it but if I just switch to YF
去看 但如果我换成YF
frame you can see what it's doing so
你可以看到它是怎么做的
it's created this breakaway shape here
它在这里创造了这个分离的形状
an entirely new face um that's
一个全新的面孔 嗯 那是
completely separate to what we've got
与我们所拥有的完全不同
there
那里
currently and what this means is if we
目前 这意味着如果我们
go to object mode you can see it's it's
转到对象模式您可以看到它是它是
not just like continuing this form here
不仅仅是在这里继续这种形式
it's pulled it Down Right which is uh
它把它往下拉了 这是呃
exactly what we want and in fact I
正是我们想要的 事实上我
wanted to to go even further than that
想要走得更远
so I'm going to select those two
所以我要选择这两个
vertices and I'm going to pull it down
顶点 我要把它拉下来
again um and then I'll do it again and
再来一次 然后我再来一次
the reason I've done this one two 3 is
我做这个一二三是因为
that this detail here is important so
这里的细节是如此重要
that it conforms to the shape of the dut
它符合尘土的形状
CU if there's not enough you're going to
CU如果你没有足够的钱
have that clipping issue that I showed
有我展示的剪裁问题
you earlier so that's pretty good and
你早些时候 所以这很好
now we're going to do it again
现在我们要再来一次
originally in my earlier
最初是在我的早期
version versions of the donut I only did
我只做了几个版本的甜甜圈
like one of these but then I noticed
就像这些中的一个 但后来我注意到
that that in the render the final render
在渲染的最终渲染中
it's often the most interesting part of
这通常是最有趣的部分
the dut so now I'm thinking yeah just do
所以现在我在想 是的 就这么做吧
it all the way around the dut just uh
它一直绕着垃圾堆 只是呃
add the bit that looks cool add more of
添加看起来很酷的部分添加更多
that so here so wherever there's
所以在这里 所以无论哪里有
essentially like a big dip is what I'm
从本质上讲 我就像是在大跌
looking for like where the the liquid
寻找液体在哪里
would sort of build up and then like the
会逐渐积累起来 然后就像
surface tension there would be just too
表面张力就会太大
much and then it would break away and it
太多了 然后它就会分开 它
would go
将会离开
down down underneath like that and we'll
就像这样下去 我们就会
do another one here why
为什么在这里再做一次？
not like that and down and
不是那样的 然后向下
down and that's pretty good haha lovely
向下 这很好 哈哈 可爱
so that concludes finally this this
所以这就结束了这一次
heavy part of the tutorial so if you're
教程的重头戏 所以如果你
ready to watch the next part I hope
我希望准备好观看下一部分
you're not giving up you can click there
你没有放弃 你可以点击那里
on the screen and I'll see you there
在屏幕上 我会在那里见到你
make sure you hit subscribe as well if
请确保您也点击订阅 如果
you haven't uh a large number of you
你们还没有呃有很多人
don't but if you want to see more
不 但如果你想看更多
Blended tutorials
混合教程
that's what you need to do
这就是你需要做的
self-promotion right there thanks guys
自我推销就在那里谢谢伙计们
see you in the next part
下一部分见